aladdin.com 2017-06-06

# Gemalto's Privacy Policy

​​Effective date: 30 June, 2014

## Introduction

We have tried to write this privacy policy in an easy to read manner doing our best to move away from legalese dense prose that could be a challenge to understand. If you have any questions or if you believe that this policy can be improved, do not hesitate to contact us via e-mail at: [privacy@gemalto.com](mailto:privacy@gemalto.com).

In this policy,

  * “user” or “you” means any person using the Service, whether by browsing our websites or using our mobile apps, purchasing products, subscribing to our Newsletter, to “Get in touch with us”, or participating in any other activities available through the Service.
  * Gemalto or "we" or "us" or "our" or other similar pronouns means Gemalto S.A.

First note that since the registrant of the domain name is Gemalto S.A. a company organized under the law of France, this Privacy Policy is based on the laws and regulations of France.

## 1- To whom does this privacy policy apply?

This privacy policy is designed to inform visitors and users of the Gemalto websites (www.Gemalto.com and www.Gemalto.fr), users of our mobile applications, users and visitors of our webpages, as well as users and visitors of other Gemalto websites (for example boutique.gemalto.com) that contain a legal link to another Gemalto website (for example www.Gemalto.com), how we gather and use information collected by us via interaction with our web windows and mobile applications (hereafter collectively referred to as the “On-Line Service”).

Note that by using our On-Line Service you are consenting to our use of the information collected as set forth in this privacy policy document. If you are in disagreement with the terms of this privacy policy document do not use our On-Line Service.

## 2- What information do we collect?

  1. **Technical information we obtain when you use our On-Line Service**. As you may know, when you access a website or use a mobile application there is some information that is automatically recorded. Our On-Line Service is not different. These are the type of technical information we are recording: 
    1. When you visit, access or use our On-Line Service our servers automatically collect and retain information based on that usage. Website log data may contain your Internal Protocol address, the address of the webpage you visited, your browser type and settings, thE date and time of your access, how you used the On-Line Service and other web tracking features (below we are providing you with a detailed explanation on the other web tracking features we use).
    2. We may also collect information about the device (PC, MAC, mobile phone, tablet, etc.) you are using to connect to the On-Line Service. Such information may include the type of device, the operating system you are using, device settings, and unique device identifiers. The collection of this information depends on the device you are using and its settings. To learn about the information your device makes available you should check the policies of your device manufacturer or software provider.
  2. ****

**Information you voluntarily provide.** When you click on the link "Subscribe to Our Newsletters" we give you the option to subscribe to our Newsletters, press releases and the Review magazine. If you decide to subscribe you voluntarily provide us with certain identifying information such as your name (first and last), address, company name and e-mail address, as well as any areas of interest. 

Likewise if you decide to contact us using the "Get in touch with us" form, you voluntarily provide us with certain identifying information such as your name (first and last), your country, and e-mail address.

Also, note that when you are registering to our Newsletters, complete the form "Get in touch with us" you are providing us with identifying information that we will be using to also send you marketing communications about the Gemalto group, our products and services, events to which we will be participating and invitation to some events.

​In light of the above, in order to be able to receive our newsletter, benefit from "Get in touch with us" and receive marketing communications from Gemalto, you need a valid email address. The email address that you give to us will to that effect be checked, in order to certify both that you are actually the owner of this address and that the owner of this address authorizes receipt of the newsletter, information related to "Get in touch with us", marketing communications (double opt-in process). Upon your registration for our newsletter, "Get in touch with us" we will save your IP address and the time and date of your registration. This serves for our part as a safeguard, should a third party attempt to misuse your email address and to subscribe to the newsletter, or "Get in touch with us" without your knowledge.

  3.  **Web tracking features we use.**
    1. **Cookie data.** We put in place a specific Cookie Policy that you can view from the link. The Cookie Policy will describe what is a cookie and why we use cookies. Please note, unless you choose to voluntarily identify yourself to us via our On-Line Service, cookies will not directly indentify you. As you read in the Cookie Policy you have the possibility to refuse cookies by configuring your browser to do so; if you do you may not be able to use some of the features of our On-Line Service and may not be able to access certain parts of our On-Line Service. To be more specific this is an explanation (this not an advice or recommendation of any kind) of the pros and cons of disabling cookies. 

Pros of disabling cookies 

      1. Privacy – Some cookies, called tracking cookies, allow third-party websites or websites that are affiliated to the websites you visit to track and record the websites that you’ve been to. These third parties can be advertisers or even the government, in some cases. Disabling cookies will, therefore, keep your browsing details private.
      2. Security – Although in general, cookies are not harmful, there have been some browsers that were found to allow malicious content to access the computers where cookies are stored.
      3. Secrecy.

Cons of disabling cookies 

      1. Convenience – Cookies are actually designed to remember information about forms and websites. Cookies are responsible for the auto-fill feature for forms where you input your address or email information. If you disable cookies, you would have to fill the forms up yourself.
      2. Personalization – Personalized content, such as the text “Welcome back, Eric!” on various home pages are possible through cookies. This will not work if cookies are disabled.
    2. **Web Beacons:** Another online identification mechanism is called a web beacon, also known as a pixel tag or clear GIF. A web beacon is a clear graphic image of a 1x1 pixel that is delivered through a web browser or a HTML compliant e-mail client application to an end-user’s device. We use web beacon to enable us to evaluate the usage of our On-Line Service, target campaigns, upgrade information we provide, and know whether you have visited a web page or received a message.
    3. **Analytics collection.** We use comScore’s Digital Analytix and occasionally Google Analytics to help us anonymously track and report your behavior information and standard log information to the On-Line Service. This information helps us analyze and evaluate how the On-Line Service is used as part of our ongoing efforts to improve our On-Line Service. Note that no personally identifying data (meaning data that permit to directly identify you as a unique person) is included in this type of reporting. Google Analytics and comScore may have access to your information only for the purposes of performing these tasks on behalf of Gemalto and under obligation similar to those in this privacy policy. If you wish to know more about the terms that govern Google Analytics, please visit the Google Analytics terms of service at [www.google.com/analytics/terms](http://www.google.com/analytics/terms). For comScore’s privacy policy, visit <http://dax-files.comscore.com/digitalanalytix/EU/privacy_policy/Privacy_policy_DigitalAnalytix_EN.pdf>. 
  4. **Credit card information**  
For purchase products through our On-Line Service we use the service of a third party for processing credit card payments. This intermediary has access to personal information needed to perform its function, it is solely a link in the distribution chain and is not permitted to store, retain or use the information provided except for the sole purpose of credit card payment processing but may not use it for other purposes.

## 3\. How do we use the information we collect?

**We use the information collected to undertake the On-Line Services.  
** Only the information you have voluntary provided as described in paragraph 2(b) above is used to send you the documents and information you have selected, possibly also to contact you to discuss your interest in the On-Line Service, our products and services, send you information about promotions or events. Thus, you understand that you can receive marketing communications. Please read paragraph 4 below that gives you some choices in controlling our use of the information collected.

**The credit card information collected from you** is used to collect payment from you.

**Regarding analytics collection** please note that we will not (and will not allow any third party to) use the statistical analytics tool to track or to collect any of your personally identifiable information. We will not associate any data gathered from our On-Line Service with any personally identifiable information (meaning data that permit to directly identify you as a unique person) from any source, unless you voluntarily submit that information via a fill-in form on our On-Line Service.

**Any and all information** which is voluntarily submitted in feedback forms on our On-Line Service or any survey we initiate that you accept to take part in is only used for the purposes of reviewing this feedback and improving our On-Line Service.

**We may undertake international transfer.** Indeed we may in the process of providing On-Line Service to you, transfer information that we collect about you, including personally identifiable information (meaning data that permit to directly identify you as a unique person), across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. If you are located in regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from the laws of France, please note that by using the On-Line Service you are consenting and permitting the transfer of information, including personal information, to countries and jurisdictions that may not have the same data protection laws as your jurisdiction. 

## 4\. What choice do you have about sharing your information?

  1. **You may request to be removed** from marketing communications by visiting this page: http://www.gemalto.com/companyinfo/optout and requesting that you be unsubscribed from future communications. A link to this page would also be found at the bottom of our e-mails pushing the information to you. 
  2. **You may update or change your registration information** via http://www.gemalto.com/companyinfo/subscription
  3. **Since the platform where you information is processed** is located in France please note this benefit: all candidates having access rights may obtain, modify or delete information about themselves (article 38 of the French law n° 78-17 of the 6th January 1978 on Data Processing, Data Files and Individual Liberties).

## 5\. With whom do we share information we collect?

  1. **We share:** We may share the information collected with hosting partners to provide the necessary hardware, software, networking, storage, and other technology and services required to operate and maintain the On-Line Service. Consequently we are making you aware that certain of the information collected may be transferred from your current location to our offices and servers as well as the hosting partner we indicate in this paragraph. We are careful to only provide to the hosting partner the information that is necessary to assist us in providing the On-Line Service. 

We may also share the information collected with companies that are part of the Gemalto legal organization and that are located in different countries of the world. 

  2. **Credit card:** we use a third-party intermediary to manage credit card processing. This intermediary is not permitted to store, retain, or use your billing information except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on our behalf. 
  3. **We do not share:** We do not rent, sell, or share any information about you with any third-parties.
  4. **We may share:** We may also provide non-personal, summary or group statistics about the traffic patterns of our On-Line Service, and information covering the usage of our On-Line Service to reputable third-party, but these statistics will include no personal information (meaning data that could directly identify you as a unique person). 
  5. **We may disclose:** We may disclose the information collected if we believe such action is necessary to: 
    1. comply with the law, or legal process served on us;
    2. protect and defend our rights or property (including the enforcement of our agreements); or
    3. act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of our On-Line Service or members of the public.

## 6\. Children’s privacy

The On-Line Service is not directed to anyone under 18 years of age. If you are under 18 years old do not use the On-Line Service.

## 7\. Community blog

The On-Line Service offer a voluntary community blog web page where we make message boards and forums available to you, you are solely responsible for the information and any other content you post on and through the community blog webpage and should be aware that when you voluntarily disclose personal information (meaning data that permit to directly identify you as a unique person) on or through the community blog webpage, such information is generally accessible to, and may be collected and used by, other users. This may result in unsolicited messages from third parties, and such messages are beyond our control. We do not exercise control over the users of the community blog webpage, and we are not responsible and do not accept any liability whatsoever, for any collection or use of information you may disclose through the community blog webpage. This privacy policy does not cover the disclosure of information via the community blog webpage. We encourage that you exercise discretion when providing personal information about yourself in and through community blog webpage. You are responsible for the content of any Information you put on the community blog webpage. We have no obligation to, and do not in the normal course, monitor or control any Information that is or becomes available on community blog webpage. We reserve the right to review any Information that is or becomes available on community blog webpage. We reserve the right to refuse to post or to edit or remove, in whole or in part, any Information that is, in our sole discretion, unacceptable, undesirable. We have no obligation to exercise such reservation of rights; however, We respect the copyright law and consequently we may terminate access for content providers or forum participants who are found repeatedly to provide or post protected material without necessary rights and permissions.

By submitting information through the community blog webpage, you grant us a perpetual, royalty-free, worldwide license to use, transmit, copy and display such information in any and all media now know or hereinafter devised and represent that you have all necessary rights in such posting.

Now that you have been warned, let us tell you about the community blog webpage. The community blog webpage connects you with others to share your questions, insights, and views about the On-Line Service and Gemalto. Read what others are saying about the On-Line Service and Gemalto, get knowledgeable answers, and swap comments and ideas on the On-Line Service and Gemalto with others.

The community blog webpage is available only to individuals older than 18 years of age.

Please use the community blog webpage with respect as if you were interacting with your friends. 

**Do not post:**

  * Profane or obscene, inflammatory or spiteful comments 
  * Messages that abuse, denigrate or threaten others 
  * Text or articles written by someone else, even with attribution for the author, except for brief quotations from a book, article or other product related to the discussion 
  * Any personal information about person under 18. 
  * Descriptions that intrude on the privacy of another person, including revealing personally identifiable information such as their name or address 
  * Text that promotes illegal or immoral conduct 
  * Repeated posts that make the same point excessively 
  * Repeated unwelcome messages that harass or embarrass other participants 
  * Any form of "spam," including advertisements, contests, or other solicitations for other websites or companies; or any URL link that includes a "referrer" tag or affiliate code
  * Do not impersonate another person.

## 8\. Gemalto and social networking

We may collect information about you in connection with social networking sites in several ways, such as:

  * When you choose to join (or “like”) a Gemalto page on a social networking site (such as the Gemalto page on Facebook). In these situations, the social networking site may make some information about you available to Gemalto. Please see the privacy policy for the social networking site to learn more.
  * When you interact with a Gemalto social networking page or content, we may use cookies to learn which links you clicked (please refer to the paragraphs 2(c) above about cookies and how we use the information collected).
  * When you make information publicly available on your social networking page, we may collect that information.
  * When you make use of the Social Sign-In feature to access content in lieu of submitting a web form. The Social Sign-In feature allows Web form visitors the opportunity to connect to your online programs using their social network identity. Visitors can use their existing social networking site such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, or Salesforce to bypass a registration or sign-up Web form. Social Sign-In captures visitors’ current contact information and stores the information directly into the database.

We use this information for purposes described in the paragraph 3 above.

To learn more about the privacy practices of a social networking site on which you interact with Gemalto, please refer to the privacy policy for that social networking site.

## 9\. Business transaction

In the event that we go through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, the information collected will likely be among the assets transferred. As part of such a transaction we will require from the acquirer to commit to the same level of protection described in this privacy policy. We will post a notice on our website of any such change in ownership or control that could affect the On-Line Service.

## 10\. Changes to this policy 

We reserve the right to amend or update this privacy policy at any time. You can always review the most current version of this privacy policy at any time at: www.gemalto.com/companyinfo/privac​y-policy​. Pay attention to the effective date of the privacy policy appearing at the top of it since it indicates the privacy policy applicable. If we decide to modify the privacy policy, we will post an announcement on the On-Line Service. We could also send you an e-mail prior to the change becoming effective. Once the change is effective please understand that your continued use of the On-Line Service demonstrates your agreement to the changes to the privacy policy. If you do not want to be bound by the changes to the privacy policy you have to cease using the On-Line Service.

## 11\. Do not track for resident of the state of California (U.S.A)

Do not Track (or “DNT”) is a preference you could set in your browser (provided your browser permit such selection) to let the sites you visit know that you do not want them collecting certain information about you.

We do not respond to DNT signal. We do not treat differently the person whose browsers send a DNT signal differently from those without one.

Please note that except for our On-Line Service we do not collect personally identifiable information about you when you move across other websites.

## 12\. Contact information

Questions regarding this privacy policy have to be directed at [privacy@gemalto.com](mailto:privacy@gemalto.com).
